Hi my name is Mary Thinnes and I'm a skin care expert.
I'm going to go through prepping the skin to repair it for the chemical peels.
First, what you want to do is put on gloves to protect your hands because it will cause peeling on your hands.
And obviously you don't want that.
Then you're going to cleanse the skin.
I'm going to take a brush, dip it in some water, put some of the cleansing gel on it, and then I'm going to cleanse the skin.
You want to do it in just a circular motion.
Don't be too aggressive on the skin just cleanse it.
Just making sure you get off all the impurities so that your skin is properly prepped for the peel.
And so that the chemicals and treatments that you're going to do from here on out are actually going to penetrate into cleansed skin not contaminated skin.
After you've rinsed off the cleanser off the skin, you want to prep the skin with the papaya.
Papaya is going to break down those dead skin cells and its going to help the chemicals penetrate into the skin as well.
If you have dead skin cells built up on the surface, nothing is going to come in and nothing is going to go out.
So it won't be effective.
Basically papaya is just a little bit of like a gel as you can tell.
And you want to put it on the skin.
And since most people don't have a steamer at home, you want to keep it on the skin for about twenty minutes without steam.
If you have a steamer you want to keep it on the skin for ten minutes.
But, without a steamer, you're going to keep it on for twenty.
And then, once twenty minutes is up, you're going to remove it with a wet cloth.
And that's the first step in prepping the skin for chemical peels.